<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on dunamismax.com</title>
    <link>https://dunamismax.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on dunamismax.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 22:47:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dunamismax.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Being alone on New Years is dope actually</title>
      <link>https://dunamismax.com/blog/being-alone-on-new-years-is-dope-actually/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 22:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dunamismax.com/blog/being-alone-on-new-years-is-dope-actually/</guid>
      <description>being alone on New Years is dope actually Spending New Year’s Eve alone can sound like a bummer in theory, but in practice, it can be downright glorious. Instead of fielding invites to noisy gatherings or pretending to enjoy stale party mixes, I decided to go deep into learning Rust and treat myself to a night of unhurried coding, crispy nuggets, and a classic sci-fi action flick.&#xA;Diving into Rust on New Year’s Eve As an IT Director by day, I often juggle a variety of systems and priorities, but at night I switch gears into Rust enthusiast mode.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I am learning Rust</title>
      <link>https://dunamismax.com/blog/why-i-am-learning-rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 21:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dunamismax.com/blog/why-i-am-learning-rust/</guid>
      <description>Why I Am Learning Rust Over the past few years, Rust has emerged as a powerful, modern programming language that combines high performance with robust safety guarantees. I first stumbled upon Rust when reading about memory safety and concurrency, two areas where many languages struggle or require significant caution. This piqued my curiosity: Could Rust be the language that balances low-level control with user-friendly tooling, making safer systems code more accessible?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hosting a Hugo blog on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://dunamismax.com/blog/hosting-a-hugo-blog-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dunamismax.com/blog/hosting-a-hugo-blog-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few days, I’ve set up a Hugo-based blog on an Ubuntu server. From installing Hugo and picking a theme to customizing layouts, adding a contact form, and tweaking the favicon, it’s been a step-by-step learning process.&#xA;Installing Hugo &amp;amp; Starting a New Site After installing Hugo (Extended) via apt, I ran:&#xA;hugo new site dunamismax.com This created the basic structure. Using:&#xA;hugo server -D I previewed changes instantly.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
